National Council for the Traditional Arts (NCTA) collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
National Council for the Traditional Arts (NCTA) collection circa 1961-2008
AFC 2001/019
National Council for the Traditional Arts
18,794 items; 6,025 containers.
36 containers: 12,600 manuscript materials.
985 sound tape reels: analog.
3291 Digital Audio Tapes (DAT): digital.
704 sound cassettes: analog.
205 sound files: digital, WAV files (96 kHz, 24 bit and 44.1 kHz, 16 bit)
6 videocassettes: analog.
1003 sound discs (CD-R): optical; 4 3/4 in.
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Collection of concert and workshop recordings of events at the National Folk Festivals, Lowell Folk Festivals, and other festivals, tours, and concerts sponsored by the National Council for the Traditional Arts (NCTA), formerly the National Folk Festival Association founded in 1934. Features performances and traditions from throughout the United States and from around the world.
Provenance
National Council for the Traditional Arts; Donation; 2001.
Accruals
No further accruals expected.
Related Material
National Folk Festival, 1938 [sound recording]. https://lccn.loc.gov/2009655367
National Folk Festival, 1952 [sound recording]. https://lccn.loc.gov/2008700385
National Folk Festival, 1954 [sound recording]. https://lccn.loc.gov/2008700386
National Folk Festival, 1960 [sound recording]. https://lccn.loc.gov/2010655217
National Folk Festival, 1972, Area 1, Area 2, Area 3 [sound recording]. https://lccn.loc.gov/2013655490
National Folk Festival, 1972, Area 1 [sound recording]. https://lccn.loc.gov/2012655213
Access and Restrictions
The National Council for the Traditional Arts collection is open for research. To request materials, please contact the Folklife Reading Room at https://hdl.loc.gov/loc.afc/folklife.contact
Scope and Content
Collection of concert and workshop recordings of events at the National Folk Festivals, Lowell Folk Festivals, and other festivals, tours, and concerts sponsored by the National Council for the Traditional Arts (NCTA), formerly the National Folk Festival Association founded in 1934. Features performances of ballads, blues, bluegrass, contra dance music, country music, cowboy songs, fiddle tunes, folk music, gospel music, hymns, old-time music, singer songwriters, steel band music, storytelling, Western swing, and more; with numerous performers playing music from African, African American, American Indian, Cajun, Canadian, Caribbean, Eastern European, Hawaiian, Irish, Latin American, Mexican, Scottish, Sea Islands, Sicilian, Ukrainian, and many other traditions from throughout the United States and from around the world. Manuscripts include documentation from the containers of the original sound recordings.
The collection includes a database with track-level information, performers associated with each track, musical styles, identifiers, and technical metadata about the recordings. Recording artists and music categories are listed in the Primary Recording Artists and Genres lists in this finding aid. Complete lists of performers can be found in the Appendix: Full List of Recording Artists. Please contact the Folklife Reading Room with requests.
Arrangement
The bulk of the collection (series 1) are recordings, which are divided into subseries according to the type of event documented (music and folklife or field recordings). Most physical carriers (tape reels, cassettes, DATs, and CD-Rs) have been digitized. NCTA original identifiers were replaced by sr (sound recording) identifiers. Original identifiers have been maintained in the NCTA database, where there are corresponding sr numbers. Series 2 encompasses paper materials removed from tape boxes, inventories, lists of artists, and container documentation from original sound recording formats.
Series 1. National Council for the Traditional Arts (NCTA) events and other recordings, ca. 1961-2008
Subseries 1. Music and folklife events, ca. 1971-2008
Subseries 2. Field recordings, ca. 1961-2007
Series 2. Physical recordings documentation, ca. 1961-2009
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Ardoin, Chris; Ayala, Pedro; Baker, Etta, 1913-2006; Baker, Kenny, 1926-2011; Ball, Marcia; Barnes, Brady, 1908-1986; Barnes, Lucy; Bass, Fontella; Bellar, Johnny; Bergey, Barry; Best, Carroll, 1931-1995; Blazonczyk, Eddie; Boyer, Horace Clarence, 1935-2009; Bright, Fletcher; Bruce, Vin; Burris, J. C., 1928-1988; Butler, Henry (Pianist); Cage, Bob, 1923-2014; Cahill, Dennis; Cano, Nati, 1933-2014; Carroll, Liz; Casserino, Matteo; Cephas, John; Chavis, Boozoo, 1930-2001; Collins, Cal, 1933-2001; Connolly, Séamus; Cooney, Michael B., 1943-; Cormier, J. P. (John Paul); Cormier, Joseph; Courville, Sady; Cruz, Lorenzo; Cuesta, Iván; D. R. (Dalton Roberts); Dahlin, Paul; Daigrepont, Bruce; Damessae, Seleshe; Daugherty, Junior; Delafose, Geno; Delafose, John, 1939-1994; Derrane, Joe; Dickey, Lotus; Doucet, David; Doucet, Michael; Douglas, Jerry, 1956-; Doyle, Danny, 1940-2019; Doyle, John, 1971-; Duskin, Big Joe, 1921-2007; East, Ernest; Egan, Séamus, 1969-; Ellis, Tony (Banjoist); Ellis, Wilbert, 1914-1977; Flippen, Benton; Ford, Brownie; Fraley, Annadeene; Fraley, J. P.; Frank, Keith, 1972-; Gaffney, Brian (Musician); Galbraith, Art, 1909-1993; Grcevich, Jerry, 1951-; Griffith, James S.; Gutiérrez, José (Gutiérrez Ramón); Hagopian, Richard A., 1937-; Haleamau, Karin; Hayes, Martin, 1961-; Henderson, Wayne; Hinton, Algia Mae, 1929-2018; Holeman, John Dee; Holloway, Quentin; Hooven, Greg; Howard, Clint, 1930-; Ivers, Eileen; Jackson, John, 1924-2002; Jiménez, Santiago, Jr., 1944-; Kaapana, Ledward; Keane, Sean; Kimbrough, James; Kirchen, Bill; Knott, Sarah Gertrude, 1895-1984; Kouyate, Djimo; Krauss, Alison, 1971-; LaBeef, Sleepy, 1935-2019; Lamond, Mary Jane; Lang, Julian, 1951-; LaPrelle, Elizabeth; Lawson, Doyle; Little, Jeff T.; Locke, Kevin; Lohman, Jon; Lynch, Claire; MacMaster, Natalie; Magic Slim (Musician); Mainer, Wade, 1907-2011; Mangan, Patrick; Marshall, Brian (Musician); Martin, Reed (Banjoist); Martinez, Roberto, 1929-; McCann, Gordon, 1931-; McCoury, Del, 1939-; McGee, Dennis; McIntyre, Chuna; McKenna, Antoinette; Menard, D. L.; Mighty Sparrow, 1935-; Mitchell, Fleeta, 1913-; Mitchell, Nathaniel, 1912?-; Moloney, Mick, 1944-2022; Morrison, Harold; Mouton, Walter; Mulvihill, Brendan, 1954-; Nguyẽ̂n, Thuyé̂t Phong; O'Hare, Kieran; O'Sullivan, Jerry, 1959-; Ohrlin, Glenn, 1926-2015; Olin, Julia; Paisley, Danny, 1959-; Paulin, Ernest, 1907-2007; Pearson, Barry Lee; Pennington, Eddie; Pierson, Leroy Jodie; Pleasants, Dick; Quimby, Doug, 1936-2006; Quimby, Frankie; Raghavan, Jothi; Riley, Steve (Singer); Robinson, Debbie, 1965-; Robinson, Lavaughn; Rockin' Dopsie, Jr.; Roheim, Anund, 1913-; Ross, Dr. (Isaiah), 1925-1993; Ross, Gayle (Singer); Roy, Gilles (Dancer); Saldivar, Mingo; Sapoznik, Henry; Savoy, Marc; Severe, Duff; Sheehy, Daniel, 1947-; Shelor, Sammy; Sizemore, Whit; Slyde, Jimmy; Spitzer, Nicholas R.; Spottswood, Richard K. (Richard Keith); Sproat, Clyde Halemaʻumaʻu, 1930-2008; Sredzienski, Gary; St. Pierre, Simon; Stanky, John; Stanley, Ralph; Sutphin, Kirk; Tanner, Gordon, 1916-1982; Thompson, Hayden; Ti-Coca; Tipton, Carl; Toups, Wayne, 1958-; Townsend, Henry; Trowbridge, Kenneth; Van Arsdale, Paul; Viesca, Juan; Vinagre, Ana Bela; Walden, Charlie; Wallace, Andy; Wallin, Doug, 1919-2000; Walser, Don; Wang, Yuqin, 1946-; Watson, Dale; Watson, Doc; White, Buck; Williams, Claude, 1908-2004; Williams, Warner; Wilson, Joe, 1938-2015; Wine, Melvin
Organizations
American Indian Music and Dance Troupe; Appalachian Trail (Musical group); Armstrong Twins; Back Step Band; Badgett Sisters; Barachois (Musical group); Beausoleil (Musical group); Beginish (Musical group); Birmingham Sunlights (Musical group); Blind Boys of Alabama; Blue Highway (Musical group); Bluegrass Mountaineers; Boys of the Lough; BR549 (Musical group); Brave Old World (Musical group); Cana Ramblers (Musical group); Canterbury Country Dance Orchestra; Cellicion Family Singers; Cephas & Wiggins; Chaksam-Pa Tibetan Dance and Opera Company; Chatuye (Musical group); Cherish the Ladies (Musical group); Comhaltas Ceoltóirí Éireann. Hanafin-Cooley Branch; Danú (Musical group); Dervish (Musical group); Double Clutchin' (Musical group); Dry Branch Fire Squad; Ecos de Borinquen (Musical group); Eddie Blazonczyk's Versatones; Eller Brothers; Eunice Playboys (Musical group); Fantasmas del Valle (Musical group); Filé (Musical group); Flint Nation Singers; Four Eagle Gospel Singers; French Rockin' Boogie (Musical group); Front Porch String Band; Ganga (Musical group); Git-Hoan (Dance troupe); Green Fields of America (Musical group); Grupo Fantasma; Harley Allen-Mike Lilly Band; Harmonia (Musical group); Highwoods String Band; Holmes Brothers; Houserockers (Musical group: Hezekiah Early); Inca Son (Musical group); James King Band; Johnson Mountain Boys; Karl and the Country Dutchmen; Livesay Quartet; Lost Bayou Ramblers; Louisiana Aces (Musical group); Lynn Morris Band; Lúnasa (Musical group); Mamou Playboys; Mariachi Jalisco; Mariachi Los Camperos de Nati Cano; Marimba Chiapas; Marimba Continental (Musical group); Nashville Bluegrass Band; National Council for the Traditional Arts; National Folk Festival (U.S.); Next Generation (Choral group); No Speed Limit (Musical group); Oinkari Basque Dancers (Boise, Idaho); Paschall Brothers; Pine Ridge Boys; Pleneros de la 21 (Musical group); Pregoneros del Puerto; Pure Texas Band; Quebe Sisters Band; Quicksilver (Musical group); Red Clay Ramblers; Reyes de Albuquerque (Musical group); Roan Mountain Hilltoppers; Ross County Farmers; Scott Playboys; Shady Mountain Ramblers; Smokey Valley Boys; Smoking Bluegrass (Musical group); Soileau Zydeco Band; Solas (Musical group); Springfield Exit (Musical group); Stepping Ambassadors; Sun Rhythm Section; Ta Pethia; Too Much Fun (Musical group); Tremendos Cuatro Espadas (Musical group); Union Station (Musical group); Valley Ramblers (Musical group); Vent du nord (Musical group); Vishtèn (Musical Group); Wanga-Nègès (Musical group); Whitetop Mountain Band; Whitstein Brothers; Wylie & the Wild West (Musical group); Yuri Yunakov Ensemble; Zydecajun (Musical group); Zydeco Cha-Chas (Musical group)
Subjects
Acadians--Music.; Ballads, English--Appalachian Region.; Basket making.; Basque Americans--Music.; Bluegrass music.; Blues (Music); Boogie woogie & barrelhouse piano.; Buck dance.; Cajun music--Louisiana.; Cajun music.; Calypso (Music); Cherokee Indians--Folklore.; Conjunto music--Mexico.; Conjunto music--Texas.; Country music.; Cowboys--Poetry.; Cowboys--Songs and music.; Fiddle tunes--Appalachian Region.; Fiddle tunes--Ireland.; Fiddle tunes--Ozark Mountains Region.; Folk dance music--Appalachian Region.; Folk dance music--Ireland.; Folk dance music--Nova Scotia--Cape Breton Island.; Folk festivals--United States.; Folk music festivals--United States.; Folk music--Hawaii.; Folk music--Ireland.; Folk music--Poland.; Folk music--United States.; Folk songs, English--United States.; Folk songs.; Funk (Music); Garifuna (Caribbean people)--Music.; Garifuna (Caribbean people)--Social life and customs.; Go-go (Music); Gospel music.; Greek Americans--Music.; Guitar music (Slack key); Indians of North America--Music.; Irish Americans--Music.; Jazz.; Klezmer music.; Music--Bulgaria.; Music--Ethiopia.; Old-time music.; Oud and percussion music.; Polish Americans--Music.; Polka (Dance); Polkas.; Rhythm and blues music.; Rockabilly music.; Sacred music.; Singer-songwriter music.; Songs, Lakota.; Songs, Zuni.; Spirituals (Songs); Step dancing--Ireland.; Storytelling.; String band music--Appalachian Region.; Tales--United States.; Tsimshian Indians--Social life and customs.; Ukrainian Americans--Music.; Vallenato (Music); Yodeling.
Form/Genre
Manuscripts.; Sound recordings; Video recordings.
Container List
- Series 1. National Council for the Traditional Arts (NCTA) events and other recordings, ca. 1961-2008
  Documentation from events in which the National Council for Traditional Arts was either the organizer or participant. Includes recordings of festival performances, musical tours, concerts, jam sessions, parties, radio broadcasts, oral history interviews, and NEA Heritage Fellowship award ceremonies. Also includes log sheets for many performances.
  - Subseries 1. Music and folklife events, ca. 1971-2008
    Recordings from musical events that NCTA organized, such as folk festivals, musical tours, concert series, and concerts.
    - 50th Anniversary Celebration of Mammoth Cave National Park, September 1, 1990, 2 recordings
      Recordings related to the Masters of the Steel String Guitar tour.
    - American Folk Festival 1982, September 20, 1982--October 15, 1982, September 20, 1982 through October 15, 1982; 25 recordings
      Recordings from Taipei, Taiwan, Bangkok, Thailand, Jakarta, Indonesia, Manila, Philippines, and Seoul, Korea. Tapes labeled as American Folklife Festival, but could be recordings from another festival (American Folk Festival began in 2002).
    - American Folk Festival 2005, August 26-28, 2005, 88 recordings
      Recordings from the American Folk Festival in Bangor, Maine.
    - American Folk Festival 2006, August 25-27, 2006, 95 recordings
    - American Folk Festival 2007, August 24-26, 2007, 82 recordings
    - American Masters of Celtic Music, January 31-February 2, 1997, 6 recordings
      Tour in Easton, Pennsylvania; New Brunswick, New Jersey; and Blue Bell, Pennsylvania.
    - Anniversary of the Park Service 75th, August 25, 1991, 2 recordings
      Boarding House Park Stage, Lowell, Massachusettes. Perhaps this is part of the Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Balladcatchers, undated, 1 recording
      This second disc is labeled Balladcatchers (first disc is labelled Gospel Ship) and is hosted by Joe Wilson with Sheila Kay Adams, Almeda Riddle, Scotty and Patsy West, Joe Heaney, Dee and Delta Hicks, Johnnie Ray Hicks, Larry Older, Jimmy Olla Belle Reed, & Clint Howard -- part of six compact discs that were broadcast on WDUQ-FM -- all were originally recorded at National Folk Festivals and include narration by Joe Wilson.
    - Ballard Branch Bogtrotters, June 28-July 2, 1994, 4 recordings
      July 2, 1994, recording, Galax, Virginia. June 28, 1994, recording location unknown, possibly Galax, Virginia.
    - Bangor concert, November 7, 2001, 2 recordings
      Original DAT labeled: "Bangor - 11/7/01 - Cherish the Ladies - Bangor, Maine - 11-7-01.
    - Best of Irish Music and Dance In America, January 20, 22, and 28th, 1978, 9 recordings
      Washington, D.C. Original tape labeled: Folk Festival USA-NPR- National Folk Festival 1974.
    - Big Apple Big Easy, March 19-28, 1998, 14 recordings
      Performances in upsate New York and Maryland showcasing New York klezmer music and traditional New Orleans jazz.
    - Blue Ridge Mountain Homecoming, December 16, 2000, 1 recording
      Galax, Virginia. Original tape labeled, "2nd Annual Blue Ridge Mountain Homecoming -- 12/16/00 -- 7:30 PM -- Rex Theater -- Galax, VA -- Wayne Henderson and Friends."
    - Blue Ridge Music Center Concert Series, 2002-2007, 129 recordings
      Concert series in Galax, Virginia.
    - Blue Ridge Parkway, 1999-2000, 10 recordings
      Concert series in Galax and Cumberland Knob, Virginia.
    - Blue Ridge Parkway 60th Anniversary, September 11, 1985, 5 recordings
      Concerts in Cumberland Knob, Virginia.
    - Bluegrass at Peaks of Otter, September 5, 1999, 1 recording
      Concert in Bedford, Virginia.
    - Border Folk Festival, 1982-1991, 95 recordings
      El Paso, Texas.
    - Border Folk Festival - Broadcast, October 4, 1986, 12 recordings
    - Cajun Stomp, undated, 1 recording
      Hosted by Joe Wilson with the Balfa Brothers, Sadie Courville & Dennis McGee, Walter Mouton and the Scott Playboys, and Beausoleil. From the collection of the NCTA Archives and were broadcast on WDUQ-FM, all were originally recorded at National Folk Festivals and include narration by Joe Wilson.
    - California Generations, October 22-1992--November 15, 1992, 36 recordings
      Concerts presented by various California universities.
    - Carter Barron Concert, September 4-5, 1993, 4 recordings
      Concert at Carter Barron Amphitheater, Washington, D.C.
    - Celebrating the Banjo, September 19, 1996, 1 recording
      Show hosted by Joe Wilson with various performers, and broadcast on WDUQ-FM Pittsburgh.
    - Celebrating the Folk Violin, September 12, 1996, 1 recording
    - Celebrating the Steel String Guitar, September 26, 1996, 1 recording
    - Country Music Tour, September 22-October 16, 1981, 38 recordings
      Bluegrass, country and gospel music were featured in this USIA Arts America tour in various cities in Portugal, Turkey, Cyprus, and Greece.
    - Country Rhythms, May 1-June 20, 1981, 100 recordings
      Tour organized for USIA Arts America presented old-time string band and zydeco music in various cities in Kenya, Republic of Seychelles, Republic of Mauritius, Botswana, Zimbabwe, Zambia, Cameroon, Gabon, Ivory Coast, and Liberia.
    - Country Roads Tour, March 8, 1981-April 1, 1981, 11 recordings
      USIA Arts America, tour featuring western swing and bluegrass in various cities in Bahrain, Tunisia, United Arab Emorates, Yemen, and Morocco.
    - Cowboy Tour, June 12-July 13, 1984, 67 recordings
      Eight working cowboys from Louisiana to Hawaii presented their brand of music, stories, and poetry to audiences on tours in the West.
    - D.C. Blues Concert, December 4, 1987, 3 recordings
      Concert in Washington, D.C.
    - Der Yidisher Caravan, April 1981-January 1982, 22 recordings
      Two tours of traditional Yiddish theater, klezmer music, cantorial and folk songs that traveled to Jewish community centers and Hebrew homes for the aging across the United States.
    - District Cultures, June 1986-June 1987, 26 recordings
      Festival in Washington, D.C.
    - Echoes of Africa, 1994-1996, 37 recordings
      An exploration of the African-folk origins of American popular music and dance through a juxtaposition of traditions from West Africa and the Georgia Sea Islands with Piedmont blues and modern tap in three national tours.
    - Echoes of Africa (Interviews), November 13-14, 1995, 3 recordings
      La Jolla, California. Interviews associated with the Echoes of Africa tours.
    - Echoes of the Ozarks, March 1982-April 1982, 16 recordings
      A tour of old-time music, stories, and dance of the Ozark region featuring outstanding performers from Arkansas, Missouri and Kansas.
    - Ethnic Heritage Festival for Montgomery County, June 13, 1998, 1 recording
      Concert series in downtown Silver Spring on June 13, 1998.
    - Festival in St. Louis (National?), undated, 1 recording
      Recording of a festival in St. Louis that could be part of the National Folk Festival.
    - Foggy Bottom Country Blues Festival, April 23, 1983, 2 recordings
      NCTA archival recordings of musical performances.
    - French Tour, March, 1981, 15 recordings
      Recordings of NCTA tour of French music.
    - From Plains, Pueblos & Tundra, 1994-1995, 27 recordings
      Two national tours and six-week USIA Arts America tour of East Asia including native American music, song and dance of the Zuni, the Lakota, and the Yup'ik.
    - Fundraiser for Senator Tom Daschle, October 7, 1991, 1 recording
      Fundraiser concert for Senator Tom Daschle.
    - Gospel Ship, undated, 1 recording
      Recordings from the National Folk Festival that were broadcast on WDUQ-FM.
    - Green Fields of America, 1979, 1982, 1984, 29 recordings
      Tours of Irish-American music and dance that visited Irish-American communities throughout the U.S.
    - Heroes of the Steel String Guitar Sampler, undated, 1 recording
      Recordings likely put together to raise money for what was to become the Masters of the Steel String Guitar Tour.
    - In Performance USA, 1985, 30 recordings
      USIA Arts America tour to the Bahamas and Jamaica, including blues and zydeco musicians, mimes, street dancers and others.
    - Irish Fire, October-November, 1997, 35 recordings
      Tour of Irish music and dance presented in the Western U.S.
    - Juke Joints & Jubilee, 1991-1992, 86 recordings
      National tours of African-American blues, R&B, gospel and juba dance.
    - Khmer Classical Dance Troupe Tour, December 12, 1981, 2 recordings
      Original cassette labeled: "Side 1 Intro of Orchestra-Followed by 1. continuation of reamkev, 2. Candle-Dance."
    - Live performance, December 6, 1987, June 19, 1987, 3 recordings
      Musical performance at the Turning Point in Piermont, New York.
    - Louisiana Creole Families, January 26, 1991, 2 recordings
      Concert at Lisner Auditorium at George Washington University.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 1st, July 26-29, 1990, 30 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 1st Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 2nd, July 25-27, 1991, 34 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 2nd Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 3rd, July 24-26, 1992, 41 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 3rd Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 4th, July 23-25, 1993, 40 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 4th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 5th, July 29-31, 1994, 34 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 5th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 6th, July 27-30, 1995, 36 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 6th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 7th, July 26-28, 1996, 32 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 7th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 8th, July 24-27, 1997, 38 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 8th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 9th, July 24-26, 1998, 53 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 9th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 10th, July 23-25, 1999, 45 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 10th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 11th, July 28-30, 2000, 39 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 11th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 12th, July 27-29, 2001, 68 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 12th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 13th, July 26-28, 2002, 69 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 13th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 14th, July 25-27, 2003, 74 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 14th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 15th, July 23-25, 2004, 69 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 15th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 16th, July 29-31, 2005, 68 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 16th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 17th, July 28-30, 2006, 77 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 17th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Lowell Folk Festival 18th, July 27-29, 2007, 80 recordings
      Recordings from various stages at the 18th Lowell Folk Festival.
    - Mammoth Cave National Park Concert, June 29, 1991, 2 recordings
      Concert at Mammoth Cave National Park in Kentucky.
    - Masters of Caribbean Music Tour, October 26-November 19, 2005, 34 recordings
      Eastern United States tour that sampled the musical traditions from the islands of the Caribbean, including Puerto Rican jíbaro, Haitian twoubadou, and Trinidadian calypso.